張 凱鵬 (ZHANG, KAIPENG)

About Me

E-mail: kpzhang@ut-vision.org Homepage: http://kpzhang93.github.io/

I am a second-year Ph.D. student in the Graduate School of Information Science and Technology at The University of Tokyo, advised by Prof. Yoichi Sato. Before coming to UTokyo, I received my M.S. degree in 2018 from National Taiwan University and B.E. degree in 2016 from Donghua University.

I was a researcher in SenseTime and did research internships at Microsoft Research Asia, Tencent AI Lab, and MMLAB of CUHK at Shenzhen. My research interest mainly lies in computer vision, deep learning, and focus on face analysis and open-world analysis. My works received 3300+ citations and 3500+ GitHub Stars.









Education

Ph.D. - The University of Tokyo, Japan

04/2019 - 03/2022

Graduate School of Information Science and Technology

supervised by Prof. Yoichi Sato

M.S. - National Taiwan University, Taiwan

09/2016 – 08/2018

Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia,

supervised by Prof. Winston Hsu.

B.E. - Donghua University, China

09/2012 - 07/2016

Computer Networking (Excellent Engineer Program)

Experience

The University of Tokyo

04/2019 - 03/2022

Ph.D. student & Research assistant

Advisor: Prof. Yoichi Sato

- Semantic segmentation, few-shot learning and active learning
- AutoML for face analysis (Tencent Rhino-Bird Elite Training Program)

SenseTime

09/2018 - 03/2019

Researcher

- Incremental large-scale face recognition learning system for ShenZhen Security Bureau

National Taiwan University Master student & Research assistant

09/2016 - 08/2018

Advisor: Prof. Winston Hsu

- Low-resolution face hallucination and recognition. ECCV 2018
- Virtual Try-On Shoe. ACCV 2018
- Disguised Faces in the Wild

1st winner of Disguised Faces in the Wild Challenge, CVPR 2018.

- Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination, CVPRW 2018
- Group-level emotion recognition in the wild

1st winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge

2nd winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge

07/2017 - 09/2017 Tencent AI Lab

Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Zhifeng Li and Dr. Wei Liu

Real-time face detection and alignment. ICCV 2017

Multimedia Laboratory, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology

07/2015 - 08/2016

Visiting student

Advisor: Prof. Zhifeng Li and Prof. Yu Qiao

- Face Recognition using proposed discriminative deep feature learning approach. ECCV 2016 & IJCV
- Joint face detection and alignment using multi-task cascaded convolutional networks. IEEE SPL
- Facial gender, smile and accessories classification using deep convolutional neural networks 1st winner of ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge - Track 2 & 3, CVPR 2016.

Publications (received 3300+ citations, June. 2020)

- 1. Zhanpeng Zhang, **Kaipeng Zhang**, "FarSee-Net: Real-Time Semantic Segmentation by Efficient Multi-scale Context Aggregation and Feature Space Super-resolution", *ICRA*, 2020.
- 2. Yandong Wen*, **Kaipeng Zhang***, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Comprehensive Study on Center Loss for Deep Face Recognition", *IJCV*, 2019 (* indicates equal contribution).
- 3. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhanpeng Zhang, Chia-Wen Cheng, Winston Hsu, Yu Qiao, Wei Liu and Tong Zhang, "Super-Identity Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *ECCV*, 2018.
- 4. Kaipeng Zhang, Ya-Liang Chang and Winston Hsu, "Deep Disguised Faces Recognition", CVPRW, 2018.
- 5. Chao-Te Chou, Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee and Winston Hsu, "Pose Invariant Virtual Try-On Shoe with Conditional Image Completion", *ACCV*, 2018.
- 6. Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Jianfei Yang, Debin Meng, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Cascade Attention Networks for Group Emotion Recognition with Face, Body and Image Cues", *ICMI*, 2018.
- 7. Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee, Chia-Wen Cheng and Winston Hsu, "Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *CVPRW*, 2018.
- 8. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhanpeng Zhang, Hao Wang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao and Wei Liu, "Detecting Faces Using Inside Cascaded Contextual CNN", *ICCV*, 2017.
- 9. Lianzhi Tan, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Group Emotion Recognition with Individual Facial Emotion CNNs and Global Image Based CNNs", *ICMI*, 2017.
- 10. Yandong Wen, **Kaipeng Zhang,** Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Discriminative Deep Feature Learning Approach for Face Recognition", *ECCV*, 2016.
- 11. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks", *IEEE SPL*, 2016.
- 12. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks", *CVPRW*, 2016.

Selected Honors & Awards

| D | |
|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|------|
| Tencent Rhino-Bird Elite Training Program | 2020 |
| MSRA Fellowship Nomination Award | 2019 |
| Disguised Faces in the Wild Workshop, CVPR 2018, Ist winner | 2018 |
| Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge, 2 nd winner | 2018 |
| Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge, 1st winner | 2017 |
| Accessories Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, Ist winner | 2016 |
| Smile and Gender Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, 1st winner | 2016 |
| Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis | 2016 |
| | |

Academic Service

Reviewer of NeurIPS, AAAI, ECCV, ICCV, CVPR, ACCV, TPAMI, TIP, TNNLS, TCSVT, TMM, Neurocomputing, and SPL.